Guide to the Manuscripts Bound in Printed Books in the Osborn Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Documents
  - Stock, Elliot ALS to W. A. Lloyd, Paternoster Row, London, 1879 Oct 29 (Box pe 203)
    Offers to purchase Shakespeare's Sonnets, newly published, on
    Lloyd's behalf.
  - Stukeley, William, 1687-1765 ALS to Maurice Johnson, n.p., 1749 May 9 (Box fpc 27)
    4 p.; 32 x 20 cm.
    Thanks for help with work on Richard of
    Westminster; provides summary of some
    writings of Richard; describes recent
    local fireworks show.
  - Swinburn, Robert "Plan and Dimensions of Robert Swinburn's garden at Chartershaugh": autograph MS, 1823 (Box pc 217)
    1 p.; 20 x 40 cm.
    Acc. by "Catalogue of Fruit Trees in
    Robert Swinburn's garden," 1822, and
    "A Catalogue of Trees in Newark
    Hudson's garden planted at
    Chartershaugh in 1756."
  - Tayler, Henrietta ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Queen's Gate, n.y. Mar 5 (Box pe 361)
    Presents book; explains other letters
    bound in.
  - Tayler, Henrietta ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Queen's Gate, 1949 Mar 22 (Box pe 361)
    Offers more information about the
    Urquart family.
  - Taylor, William F. ALS to James Dykes Campbell, South Norwood, 1889 Sep 17 (Box pd 159)
    1 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
    On publication of Coleridge text
    delays due to change of address and
    illness.
  - Taylor, William F. ALS to James Dykes Campbell, South Norwood, 1890 Jan 4 (Box pd 159)
    Illness; mistakes in various
    annotations of Coleridge text.
  - Thompson, Edward Maunde, 1840-1929 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Sunnycroft, Wells, 1920 May 10 (Box pe 264)
    Thanks for kind letter; encourages
    further study of Elizabethan
    handwriting.
  - Thorn-Drury, George, 1860-1931 ALS to Percy Simpson, South Kensington, 1928 Feb 4 (Box pe 395)
    2 p.; 15 x 11 cm.
    Expresses disappointment with Sunday Times book review; accepts dinner
    invitation.
  - Thorn-Drury, George, 1860-1931 ALS to Montague Summers, Roland Gardens, [London], 1921 Dec 22 (Box pe 186)
    3 p.; 17 x 13 cm.
    Lists dramatis personae from 1692
    quarto of The Taming of the Shrew
    discusses newly found book of
    Killigrew's plays, marked by the
    author.
  - Thorn-Drury, George, 1860-1931. ALS to [recipient unknown], [London], 1929 Feb 25 (Box pb 48)
    1 p.; 15 x 12 cm.
    Suggests that the tract ["The Character
    of a Coffee-House," 1673] is worth
    keeping, but not of great rarity.
  - Todd, William Burton, 1919- LS to James M. Osborn, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, 1954 Nov 23 (Box pe 114)
    1 p.; 28 x 21 cm.
    Presents book; describes typography
    of book including typeface and
    paper.
  - Troxell, Gilbert ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, West Haven, CT (Box pe 283)
    1 p.; 30 x 19 cm.
    Provides reading of 1597 Richard III.
  - Turner, Walter James Redfern, 1889-1946 ALS to Benn Bros., Westminster Bridge, [London], 1927 Feb 15 (Box pe 430)
    Regarding 15 musical extracts and his
    "Introduction."
  - Ventris, Edward, ca.1801-1886 ALS to Sir Henry Ellis, Cambridge, 1850 Oct 28 (Box pd 171)
    4 p.; 18 cm.
    Concerning Ellis' Obituary of Richard Smith, 1849, and laid into a copy
    of that work.
  - Walch, George T. ALS to Walter Begley, St. James's, n.y. Jan 21 (Box pe 407)
    Asks about possible subsequent book on
    the subject of Is it Shakespeare?
  - Walker, Alice, 1900- LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Bideford, Devon, 1953 Aug 26 (Box pe 217)
    Explains her method of calculating the
    number of errors in quarto three.
  - Walthen, G. A. LS to F. P. Wilson, The Hall, Hampstead, 1936 Nov 18 (Box pe 351.v2)
    Concerns Wilson's son Stephen,
    recommending him for advancement to
    senior school.
  - Walton, James Kirkwood LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Raheny, Dublin, 1957 Oct 13 (Box pe 326)
    Offers copy of a paper.
  - Walton, James Kirkwood LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Raheny, Dublin, 1958 Feb 11 (Box pe 326.v2)
    1 p.; 13 x 21 cm.
    Encloses typescript of reply to an
    article by Cairncross.
  - Warter, John Wood, 1806-1878 ALS to [unnamed recipient], West Tarring, 1844 May 30 (Box pc 77)
    With notes. About the 1559 edition of De Confessione Amantis.
  - Warwick, [first name unknown] Letter in third person to T. Wright, Southwell, 1833 May 15 (Box pd 69)
    Acknowledges receipt of cheque.
  - Washington, George Sydney Horace Lee, 1910- ALS to George Sherburn, Parode, Cambridge, 1961 Apr 17 (Box pe 183)
    2 p.; 9 x 12 cm.
  - Whiteman, Elizabeth Horsley ALS to [John Ruskin], Lamberhurst, Kent, 1907 Apr 1 (Box pd 164)
    Objects to treatment of her relatives
    in Ruskin's book; will send some more
    information.
  - Whiteman, Elizabeth Horsley [ALS] to [John Ruskin], Lamberhurst, Kent, 1907 Apr 2 (Box pd 164)
    8 p.; 15 x 10 cm.
    Contains biographical sketch of Richard
    Fall and his sister, Eliza Fall.
  - Wild, J. H. S. ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, University Clg, Oxford, 1949 Apr 25 (Box pd 35)
    Tells of two letters addressed to
    Joseph Severn and invites Garrod to
    examine them.
  - Wild, J. H. S. ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, University Clg, Oxford, 1949 May 7 (Box pd 35)
    Thanks Garrod for returning papers
    describes his great-grandfather
    Joseph Severn.
  - Wilson, Frank Percy, 1889-1963 ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Oxford, 1949 Dec 22 (Box pe 359)
    1p.; 17 x 14 cm.
  - Wilson, Frank Percy, 1889-1963 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Merton Clg, Oxford, 1955 Jan 17 (Box pe 312)
    Opines that Shakespeare did not consult
    Matthew Paris.
  - Wilson, John Dover, 1881-1969 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Balerno, Midlothian, 1943 Oct 23 (Box pe 248)
    Thanks for letter; reports good
    response to Wilson's The Fortunes of Falstaff; responds to Greg's
    comments about Falstaff.
  - Wilson, John Dover, 1881-1969 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Balerno, Midlothian, 1944 Jun 6 (Box pe 248)
    On recent death of son and nephew.
  - Wilson, John Dover, 1881-1969 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Balerno, Midlothian, 1946 Jul 31 (Box pe 323.v4)
    Thanks for help; concerns his efforts
    to have F. P. Wilson appointed Merton
    professor at Oxford; criticizes
    Forman's book.
  - Wilson, John Dover, 1881-1969 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Balerno, Midlothian, 1949 Jan 22 (Box pe 323.v8)
    Contains list of variances in Antony and Cleopatra; speculates
    about cause.
  - Wilson, John Dover, 1881-1969 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Balerno, Midlothian, 1957 Dec 21 (Box pe 326)
    Concerns J. K. Walton's submission to
    the Shakespeare Problems Series.
  - Wilson, John Dover, 1881-1969 L to John Kirkwood Walton, n.p., 1957 Dec 20 (Box pe 326)
    Thanks for Walton's submission to the Shakespeare Problems Series; suggests
    that ms. should be revised prior to
    formal submission.
  - Wimsatt, William Jurtz, Jr., 1907-1975 ALS to James M. Osborn, [New Haven], 1939 Oct 29 (Box pe 418)
    1 p.; 17 cm.
    Sending his book of verse.
  - Wise, Thomas James, 1859-1937 ALS to Frank Percy Wilson, Hampstead, 1923 Mar 19 (Box pe 56)
    3p.; 18 x 11 cm.
    Lends a book.
  - Wolf, Luna LS to James M. Osborn, New York, NY, 1966 Jan 24 (Box pe 128)
    Apologizes for omitting dedication to
    Osborn in paperback edition of René
    Wellek's Rise of English Literary History.
  - Woodward, G. S. ALS to "The BBC Commentator," Lee on the Solent, Portsmouth, 1957 Aug 20 (Box pe 59)
    Contributes personal recollections to
    portrait of Syon House.
  - Woodward, S. W. ALS to James M. Osborn, Spalding Grammar School, Spalding, 1970 Jun 14 (Box pe 187)
    1 p.; 18 x 21 cm.
    Hopes to find biographer for Maurice
    Johnson; encloses gifts.
  - Wright, Lyle H., 1903- LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Petworth (Box pe 289)
    Confirms a comma in Richard II
    informs Greg that he'll be handling
    corrections in his new job.
  - Wright, Stephen LS to J. C. Lynn, Bodleian Library, Oxford, 1937 Apr 22 (Box pb 55)
    Confirms that Bodleian has Rigaud
    papers, but cannot find volume with
    Izaak Walton's signature, nor can he
    locate portrait of Robert Sanderson.
  - Wright, William Aldis, 1831-1914 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Trinity Clg, Cambridge, 1899 Feb 9 (Box pe 323.v1)
    Concerns Greg's application to the
    Librarian; requests meeting.
  - Wright, William Aldis, 1831-1914 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Trinity Clg, Cambridge, 1900 Mar 23 (Box pe 323.v1)
    Will place Greg's book in the College
    Library.
  - Wright, William Aldis, 1831-1914 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Trinity Clg, Cambridge, 1906 Apr 5 (Box pe 323.v1)
    Thanks for copy of Pastoral Poetry and Pastoral Drama.
  - Yule, George Udny, 1871-1951 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, St. John's Clg, Cambridge, 1944 Oct 23 (Box pe 260)
    Thanks for kind notice of book.